Christina Lawrence

Portland, Oregon, United States Contact: 971-470-2598 Email: cmrhine@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/cmrlawrence
https://cml-data.github.io/cml-anaylsis.github.io/

Summary and Skills

Software Engineer with a diverse range of experience from software automation testing and software development to supporting hardware infrastructure through process automation and troubleshooting. I am currently a candidate for a Master of Science in Data Science from Willamette University. Some of the technologies I'm using include:

Javascript NodeJS Python PostgreSQL React

Linux AWS (DynamoDB, EC2, Lambda, API Gateway, RDS)

Experience

09/2014 to Present

Houghton Mifflin Harcourt (Formerly NWEA), Portland, Oregon - Staff Software Engineer

For HMH/NWEA, I:

- mentor other developers.
- participate in cross-disciplinary product teams to design new features for the product.
- currently lead a small team for a student assessment, teacher portal, and report visualization for reading fluency using Angular, React, NodeJS, Java APIs, PostgreSQL and AWS technologies.

05/2012 to 08/2014

Blackboard, Indianapolis, Indiana - Sr. QA Automation Engineer

- Built parts of the testing harness infrastructure and authored test scripts.
- Worked with Selenium, Fitness frontend, and Javascript/Node.js harness.
- Delivered automated regression scripts in an agile scrum environment.
- Provided root cause analysis and mentored automation staff locally and offshore.

03/2007 to 05/2012

Lipper, A Thomson Reuters Company, Denver, Colorado - Linux/Network Systems Engineer

Provided support for production, development, and assurance environments.

- Handled setup, maintenance, and troubleshooting for Linux and Sun UNIX servers, and EMC SAN.
- Wrote scripting and monitoring programs, handled hardware and software issues, and provided total support for the

06/2000 to 03/2006

Microchip Technology, Chandler, Arizona -

Sr. Software Engineer

- Developed features and fixed bugs for an 8-bit microcontroller C compiler toolchain.
- Contributed to tool manuals and future product enhancements.

Sr. Systems Engineer

- Supported Engineering and CAD groups with hardware and software issues.
- Maintained UNIX and Linux servers and developed internal tools for automating routine tasks.

Education

08/2023 to Present (graduation date: 08/31/2024)

Willamette University, Salem, Oregon - Master of Science in Data Science

08/1996 to 06/2000

Arizona State University, Tempe, Arizona - Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Systems Engineering